[Music]
hi there my name is Mike and if you're a
business Central admin this video is
just for you I'm going to show you how
easily you can configure co-pilot in
business Central co-pilot is the AI
powered assistant that helps people
improve productivity boost creativity
and eliminate those tedious
tasks so whether you're using co-pilot
to reconcile your bank statements or get
to Data Insights fostter or maybe get
answers to get unblocked quickly and do
things in business Central there's a
co-pilot for everyone in your
organization if you want to see co-pilot
and action check out the links I put
below this video that will give you
these really nice bite-sized videos that
you can watch about what it can do in
all of its different features so best of
all co-pilot is currently included with
your business Central online licenses at
no additional cost so what are you
waiting for let's dive in and get things
set up so here's the first bit of good
news co-pilot is just ready to use out
of the box no complex setup required no
lengthy uh model training required it
simply works as soon as you deploy your
business Central environment let me show
you on my newly created environment what
that looks like so here I have a US
environment I'm on the items list and
co-pilot already lights up and uh
suggests you know it's assistance to
help me out with this task where I can
analyze this list so the key Point here
is is as soon as you deploy a new
Sandbox a new production environment
co-pilot is ready to use if you sign up
for a free trial of business Central as
well co-pilot is ready to use if you're
a customer upgrading from let's say uh
update 24.5 to update 25 uh then
co-pilot again is ready to use unless
you've switched things off yourself I'll
talk about that in a moment so the key
thing here is it's ready to use out of
the box no complex setup is required
now we know that admins especially love
fine grain control over everything in
business Central so for that there's the
co-pilot and AI capabilities page let's
do a quick search for co-pilot in
business Central the page will appear
right here and as an admin I get
transparency and control over copilot
from this one
place now notice how all the features
all the capabilities of co-pilot are
listed here uh we have some generally
available features but then also some
features in preview as well and these
are clearly labeled as production ready
previews and what that means is it's
actually safe to use these in production
with users across your organization as
well you'll also notice that uh there's
a publisher listed here too so some of
these are published by Microsoft uh but
there's also a third-party publisher as
well fabric cam so what is this
particular feature well this came from
one of the addin apps that I've
installed or from an extension that I've
installed
but essentially um one of those apps
that I installed extends co-pilot in
business Central with all new
capabilities and they show up right here
as well in the same
list now notice also how all of these
are active in fact every time we add a
new feature a new capability that is
active by default on your environment
but if you're just not ready to work
with that feature yet uh you can always
deactivate it so let's take this one
here as an example I'll hit deactivate
I'll give a reason why we're not ready
well maybe this one is just not relevant
to our B business and from this point
forward uh it is instantly inactive and
users can't access that at all now
remember that these settings are per
environment which means that when you
make a change here it affects all users
in all companies within that
environment so there you have it the
co-pilot and AI capabilities is the
single page where you get visibility
into all those capabilities no matter
where they came from or how they're
installed and you also get to control
what's active and deactivated as
well now our customers often ask us is
copilot available in my country is it
available in my favorite language let's
demystify some of that so first of all
generally speaking every co-pilot
feature is available in all business
Central languages however only a subset
of those only some of those languages
have been rigorously verified and tested
by Microsoft those we call the supported
languages so keep in mind that we
encourage our users to use co-pilot
capabilities in those supported
languages uh but you can still use them
in any other business Central Language
just bear in mind that when you do that
with an unsupported language um it may
not perform as expected and quality may
vary depending on the context in which
you use it as
well now each feature defines its own
set of supported languages and that's an
important
point the other thing is country so
country or geographical uh availability
of these features uh generally speaking
um every co-pilot capability is
available in all countries in all
geographies now there are a few
exceptions to that rule and I would just
want to illustrate that directly in
business
Central so here I'm on my us environment
uh as you can see up here from the
company badge and you can see I've got a
couple of features that are available in
this uh in this environment and chat is
one of those features but if I switch
now to my German environment deployed in
Germany you can see how chat is actually
absent here so there will be some
features uh that are just not available
for certain environment country
localizations simply put if it's not
available it won't appear in this list
so if you're looking for the full list
of Which languages and which GEOS are
supported for every single co-pilot
feature in business Central I put a link
below this video which will take you
right there give you all of that
information all your questions will be
answered now we know that admins always
want to know how and where business data
is
used now keep in mind that co-pilot uses
Ai and more specifically it's powered by
the Azure open aai Service uh which is
part of the Azure cloud and is designed
for Enterprise use with the security
privacy compliance that you expect from
Azure now that Azure open AI service
isn't available in all regions for
business Central um so for that I want
to illustrate the difference uh from
region to region back in business
Central here so here I am back in my
German environment which is of course
deployed to my Germany Azure Data Center
and notice here how I have a switch
which allows data movement and that's
because there isn't an Azure opening eye
service in that same region uh so for
co-pilot to operate to function uh it
needs to actually contact Azure open a
service fish which resides in a
different region in this case it's in
either Sweden or in Switzerland but as
an administrator I have the power to
decide if that is something I'm
comfortable with so I can choose to turn
it off uh or turn it on um and if you
want to know exactly which region it's
going to connect with I've also dropped
a link down below this video where you
can see the entire mapping of azure uh
regions in terms of where your
environment is deployed along with where
Azure opening ey service is actually
located and where it connects to now
when data flows across geographies as it
says here data moves uh across out of
out of your region um it's only a small
amount of data and it's the prompt and
the response that you're using while
you're interacting with co-pilot so this
doesn't mean that the entire database is
moving out of region it's really just a
minimal amount of data that is used what
during those interactions with
co-pilot now let's contrast this with
what the same screen looks like like on
my us-based
environment so here you can see that
there actually is no switch uh to allow
data movement and that's simply because
in some regions there is the Azure openi
Service uh available to work with
business Central so here are us
customers as well as our customers in a
couple of other regions like India
Australia as well as United Kingdom um
don't need to actually opt into anything
data remains within that
region and I've summ that for you here
again use the link to see the entire
table of mappings between aure regions
that will make it a lot more clear for
your specific case now of course part of
data governance is security and we know
you care about security so when you use
co-pilot when a user puts co-pilot to
work um co-pilot runs under the user's
same context which means all the data
governance controls for security for
privacy and so on they apply to co-pilot
as well U now if you want to restrict
which co-pilot features your users can
actually access we've documented the uh
list of permissions the specific
permissions you can apply or deny as
well for your users to control that um
down to every single feature it's not
every feature that has that permission
but here you can see uh a couple of tips
on how to do that now when you bet on
the Microsoft cloud uh our promise to
you is that your data is your data your
customer data and what that means is
that we don't use the data from co-pilot
to train the AI models to the benefits
of others and we don't go and look at
your prompts either not unless you give
us your explicit consent uh so we want
to make sure that you feel safe and
understand that this is a compliant
system based on Azure uh where we keep
your data as safe and compliant as
possible all right well I hope you're as
excited as we are about co-pilot and are
ready to put that to work in your
organization if you like this video just
like And subscribe to our Channel you
get a whole load more of these kind of
videos and thank you so much for
watching